Finding aid for Department of Afroamerican and African Studies (University of Michigan) records, 1966-2010 (bulk 1970-1994)
Bentley Historical Library
- Audio recordings on cassettes, 1975-2001
  - Chronological events
    - Joe W. Trotter, Jr.: Black Labor in the Urban South, 1991 April 17; audiocassette; (Joe W. Trotter, Jr. Professor of History; Carnegie-Mellon University. Wednesday, April 17, 1991; 4:00 PM; Rackham West Conference Room.) (Box 35)
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-435-2]
    - M. Tshitshi Mbatha, Moffat Mogane and Pamela F. Scully: Towards a Post-Apartheid South Africa, 1991 April 18; audiocassette; (A Conversation With: M. Tshitshi Mbatha, Research Fellow, Program on Poverty, the Underclass and Public Policy; Moffat Mogane, Ph. D. Candidate Social Work; and Pamela F. Scully, Ph. D. Candidate, History. Thursday, April 18, 1991; 2:00-4:00. CAAS Library Conference Room, 214 West Engineering.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-436-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-436-2]
    - Perlita Muiruri and Max Gordon: Dakar and Harare: AAF Viewpoints, 1991 September 13; audiocassette; (Perilta Muiruri & Max Gordon: CAAS Undergraduate Students. Sponsored by the Ella Baker-Nelson-Mandela Anti-Racist Education Center and the Center for Afroamerican and African Studies. Friday, September 13, 12 - 1:30. Robert E. Hayden Lounge, 111 West Engineering Building.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-437-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-437-2]
    - Martin Bernal: Black Athena' and her Enemies, 1991 November 04; audiocassette (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-438-1]
    - Martin Bernal: Black Athena' and her Enemies, 1991 November 04; audiocassette; (Content is only 14 seconds long] Tape 2; Martin Bernal; Cornell University) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-439-1]
    - Dorceta E. Taylor: Developing an Environmental Justice Agenda: Minorities in the American and British Environmental Movements, 1992 February 17; audiocassette; (CAAS Sociology Job Talk. Monday, February 17, 1992, 3:00 P.M.CAAS Library Conference Room, 214 West Engineering Building) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-440-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-440-2]
    - Bell hooks: Feminist Theory as Liberatory Practice, 1992 February 20; audiocassette; (bell hooks is Associate Professor of English and Women's Studies at Oberlin College. She is author of "Feminist Theory from Margin to Center", "Yearning: Race, Gender, and Cultural Politics", "Breaking Bread: Insurgent Black Intellectual Life." Thursday, February 28,1992, 4pm Dennison Auditorium 8 (adjacent to the East Engineering Building). Sponsored by the Women's Studies Program and the Center for Afroamerican and African Studies at the University of Michigan.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-441-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-441-2]
    - Faculty and students: Africana studies: A student faculty dialogue on teaching and the curriculum, 1992 March 19; audiocassette; (Tape 1; Thursday, March 19, 1992 3-5:00 P.M. Robert E. Hayden Lounge, 214 West Engineering Bldg.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-442-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-442-2]
    - Faculty and students: Africana studies: A student faculty dialogue on teaching and the curriculum, 1992 March 19; audiocassette; (Tape 2; Thursday, March 19, 1992 3-5:00 P.M. Robert E. Hayden Lounge, 214 West Engineering Bldg.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-443-1]
    - Tony Gleaton: The African Presence in the Americas, 1992 March 31; audiocassette; (Tony Gleaton, nationally exhibited African American Photographer, on his documentation of the African Legacy in villages of the Costa Chica in southeastern Mexico. Tuesday, March 31, 1992 2:30-3:30 P.M. CAAS Seminar Room, 109 West Engineering Building) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-444-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-444-2]
    - Murry DePillars: Meet the artist, 1992 April 04; audiocassette; (Tape 2; Works of art by Dr. DePillars dating from 1967 to 1992 inaugurates in the CAAS Gallery; displayed: April 6 to May 1. SYMPOSIUM: AFRICAN AMERICAN ART. Dr. Murry DePillars, Dean, School of the Arts, Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, Virginia on "Africobra. A Visual Alternative." Professor Willis "Bing" Davis, Chair, Department of Art, Central State University, Wilberforce, Ohio examines "Visual Literacy and Adornment." Professor Sharon Patton, Associate Professor, History of Art and CAAS discusses "Romare Bearden. New Approaches/Old Images." April 6, 1992. 9:00 to 12:00 at the South Quadrangle Afro-American Lounge. Sponsored by The Center for Afroamerican and African Studies (CAAS), The University of Michigan. Co-Sponsored by The University of Michigan History of Art Dept. and the Michigan Chapter of the National Conference of Artists, Inc. (NCA)) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-445-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-445-2]
    - Murry DePillars: Meet the artist, 1992 April 04; audiocassette; (Tape 2; Works of art by Dr. DePillars dating from 1967 to 1992 inaugurates in the CAAS Gallery; displayed: April 6 to May 1. SYMPOSIUM: AFRICAN AMERICAN ART. Dr. Murry DePillars, Dean, School of the Arts, Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, Virginia on "Africobra. A Visual Alternative." Professor Willis "Bing" Davis, Chair, Department of Art, Central State University, Wilberforce, Ohio examines "Visual Literacy and Adornment." Professor Sharon Patton, Associate Professor, History of Art and CAAS discusses "Romare Bearden. New Approaches/Old Images." April 6, 1992. 9:00 to 12:00 at the South Quadrangle Afro-American Lounge. Sponsored by The Center for Afroamerican and African Studies (CAAS), The University of Michigan. Co-Sponsored by The University of Michigan History of Art Dept. and the Michigan Chapter of the National Conference of Artists, Inc. (NCA)) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-446-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-446-2]
    - Vincent P. Garcia and Demetrius Bady: Jumping In: The Production and Reproduction of Gang Membership in Late Capitalism, 1992 September 28; audiocassette; (The City as Contested Terrain: Fall Term; L.A. Wednesday September 28, 4 P.M., Rackham Assembly Hall. Demetrius Bady; LS&A Senior: Afroamerican and African Studies, The Program for American Culture. Vincent P. Garcia, LS&A Senior.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-447-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-447-2]
    - James Johnson, Jr.: The Los Angeles Rebellion of 1992: A Retrospective View, 1992 October 15; audiocassette; (James H. Johnson, Jr.; Director, Center for Study of Urban Poverty, UCLA. Thursday, October 15, 8 P.M. West Conference Room, 4th Floor, Horace H. Rackham Building.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-448-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-448-2]
    - Regina Freer: A Slice of the Pie: Roots of the Black-Korean Conflict, 1992 November 12; audiocassette; (The City as Contested Terrain, Fall Term; L.A. Thursday, November 21, 8 P.M., Rackham East Conference Room. Regina Freer; Graduate Student in Political Science.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-449-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-449-2]
    - Roderick K. Linzie: The Administration's Response to University of Michigan Anti-racist Student Protests, 1992 October 27; audiocassette; (Roderick K. Linzie, Ph. D. Candidate in Sociology. Tuesday, October 27, 199212:10-1:00 P.M. Robert E. Hayden Lounge, 111 West Engineering Building.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-450-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-450-2]
    - James Chaffers, Robert Chrisman, Duchess Harris, Laurita Kaigler, Robin D.G. Kelley and Samuel Craig Watkins: Spike Lee and the Black Agenda: A discussion of the new film, Malcolm X, 1992 December 04; audiocassette; (Tape 1; James Chaffers, Professor of Architecture and Afroamerican and African Studies; Robert Chrisman, Lecturer in English and Afroamerican and African Studies and Editor-Publisher of "The Black Scholar;" Duchess Harris, Graduate Student in American Studies, University of Minnesota; Laurita Kaigler, LS&A Senior in Film and Video Studies and Intern at Forty Acres and a Mule during the making of the film; Robin D.G. Kelley, Associate Professor of History and Afroamerican and African Studies; and moderated by: Samuel Craig Watkins, Graduate Student in Sociology. Friday, December 4, 1992, 4-5:30 P.M.Assembly Hall, 4th Floor, Horace H. Rackham Building.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-451-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-451-2]
    - James Chaffers, Robert Chrisman, Duchess Harris, Laurita Kaigler, Robin D.G. Kelley and Samuel Craig Watkins: Spike Lee and the Black Agenda: A discussion of the new film, Malcolm X, 1992 December 04; audiocassette; (Tape 2; James Chaffers, Professor of Architecture and Afroamerican and African Studies; Robert Chrisman, Lecturer in English and Afroamerican and African Studies and Editor-Publisher of "The Black Scholar;" Duchess Harris, Graduate Student in American Studies, University of Minnesota; Laurita Kaigler, LS&A Senior in Film and Video Studies and Intern at Forty Acres and a Mule during the making of the film; Robin D.G. Kelley, Associate Professor of History and Afroamerican and African Studies; and moderated by: Samuel Craig Watkins, Graduate Student in Sociology; Friday, December 4, 1992, 4-5:30 P.M.Assembly Hall, 4th Floor, Horace H. Rackham Building.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-452-1]
    - Tanaquil Jones, Ahmad Abdur-Rahman and Dhoruba al-Mujahid bin Wahad: [Black Panther Movement], 1993 January 21; audiocassette; (Part 1 and Part 2. Tanaquil Jones, Ahmad Abdur-Rahman and Dhoruba al-Mujahid bin Wahad: [Black Panther Movement]) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-453-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-453-2]
    - Tanaquil Jones, Ahmad Abdur-Rahman and Dhoruba al-Mujahid bin Wahad: [Black Panther Movement], 1993 January 21; audiocassette; (Part 3 and Part 4.Tanaquil Jones, Ahmad Abdur-Rahman and Dhoruba al-Mujahid bin Wahad: [Black Panther Movement]) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-454-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-454-2]
    - Tanaquil Jones, Ahmad Abdur-Rahman and Dhoruba al-Mujahid bin Wahad: [Black Panther Movement], 1993 January 21; audiocassette; (Loud machine noise in background] Part 5 and Part 6. Tanaquil Jones, Ahmad Abdur-Rahman and Dhoruba al-Mujahid bin Wahad: [Black Panther Movement]) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-455-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-455-2]
    - Tanaquil Jones, Ahmad Abdur-Rahman and Dhoruba al-Mujahid bin Wahad: [Black Panther Movement], 1993 January 21; audiocassette; (Part 7 and Part 8. Tanaquil Jones, Ahmad Abdur-Rahman and Dhoruba al-Mujahid bin Wahad: [Black Panther Movement]) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-456-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-456-2]
    - Susan Nkomo: Women in the South African Liberation Struggle, 1993 February 19; audiocassette; (Susan Nkomo, South African Anti-Apartheid activist and member of the African National Congress of South Africa, on women's issues in South Africa. She has traveled widely and has been detained and kept in solitary confinement as a result of her political activity. Wednesday, February 19th at 12:00 noon in the CAAS Lounge. 200 W. Engineering Bldg) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-457-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-457-2]
    - M. Nyathi: Memorial for Chris Hani, a South African activist, 1993 April 14; audiocassette; (Program recorded at very low level and contains loud background noise.] Chris Hani: A South African activist who was assinated on Saturday. The ANC has designated Wednesday, April 14 as a national day of mourning his murder. Speakers Include: Reverand M. Nyathi (from Detroit); M. Busi Mnyadu (from Toldeo). Wednesday April 14, 1993. Robert E. Hayden Lounge, 111 W. Eng. Bldg, 4:00 P.M.) (Box 35)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-458-1]
    - Cruse Symposium, 1993 April 22; audiocassette; (Tape 1; Cruse Symposium) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-459-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-459-2]
    - Cruse Symposium, 1993 April 22; audiocassette; (Tape 2; Cruse Symposium) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-460-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-460-2]
    - Valerie Smith: Class and Gender in Narratives of Passing, 1993 October 21; audiocassette; (Valerie Smith; Associate Professor in English University of California, Los Angeles. Thursday, October 21, 1993. 214 W. Engineering, (CAAS Library Conference Room), 12:10-1:30 pm.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-461-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-461-2]
    - Representation of African Culture in Museums, 1993 December 01; audiocassette; (Tape 1; Center for Afroamerican and African Studies, and the International Institute) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-462-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-462-2]
    - Representation of African Culture in Museums, 1993 December 01; audiocassette; (Tape 2; Center for Afroamerican and African Studies, and the International Institute) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-463-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-463-2]
    - Charles Eisendrath: WUOM Interview, 1994 March 04; audiocassette; (Interview with Professor Charles Eisendrath) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-464-1]
    - Marian Wright Edelman: Commencement, 1995 March; audiocassette; (Marian Wright Edelman speaking at the 1995 Commencement.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-465-1]
    - Matthew Countryman: Industrial Age, 1995 December 02; audiocassette; (Matthew Countryman at the Industrial Age Colloquium) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-466-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-466-2]
    - Ali Mazrui and John Walters: Interview, 1996 February 19; audiocassette; (Dr. Ali Mazrui interviewed by John Walters.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-467-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-467-2]
    - Carol Stack, 1996 February 27; audiocassette; (Carol Stack talk.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-468-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-468-2]
    - Nell Irvin Painter: Black Woman's Seminar, 1996 October 02; audiocassette; (Nell Irvin Painter at the Black Woman's Seminar Lecture series.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-469-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-469-2]
    - Loretta Ross: Black Woman's Seminar, 1996 October 23; audiocassette; (Black Woman's Seminar Lecture Series #2, Loretta Ross speaking.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-470-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-470-2]
    - Carole Boyce Davis: Black Woman's Seminar, 1996 November 13; audiocassette; (Black Woman's Seminar Lecture Series featuring Carole Boyce Davis.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-471-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-471-2]
    - Katie Cannon: Black Woman's Seminar, 1997 February 04; audiocassette; (Katie Cannon at the Black Woman's Seminar Lecture Series.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-472-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-472-2]
    - Barbara Arnwine: Black Woman's Seminar, 1997 March 04; audiocassette; (Barbara Arnwine at the Black Woman's Seminar Lecture Series.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-473-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-473-2]
    - Leith Mullins: Black Woman's Seminar, 1997 March 19; audiocassette; (Leith Mullins speaking at the Black Woman's Seminar Lecture Series.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-474-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-474-2]
    - Kimberly Crenshaw: Black Woman's Seminar, 1997 April 11; audiocassette; (Kimberly Crenshaw speaking at the Black Woman's Seminar Lecture series.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-475-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-475-2]
    - Sharon Hicks Bartlett, 1996 April 19; audiocassette; (Talk and discussion by Sharon Hicks Bartlett.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-476-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-476-2]
    - Lansana Kaba, Judith Byfield, Ibrahim Sundiata, Ajayi-Soyinka, Gwendolyn Mikell, Jeanne Toungara and Ali Mazrui: Panel on Henry Louis Gates "Wonders of the African World", 1999 November 13; audiocassette; (African Studies Associaton. Lansana Kaba, Chair of ASA, U of [Illinois]; Judith Byfield, Dartmouth; Ibrahim Sundiata, Chair of Dept of History, Howard U., Ajayi-Soyinka; Gwendolyn Mikell; Jeanne Toungara, Howard U. Dept. of History, and Ali Mazrui.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-477-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-477-2]
    - Edith Carney: Interview, 2001 May 29; audiocassette; (Edith Carney interviewed on radio station WAAM.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-478-1]
    - Boubacar Barry, undated; audiocassette; (Talk and discussion with Boubacar Barry.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-479-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-479-2]
    - Judith A. Byfield: Women, Marriage, Divorce and the Emerging Colonial State in Abeokuta (Nigeria) 1892-1904, undated; audiocassette; (Judith A. Byfield, Rockefeller Humanities Fellow, CAAS Department of History, Dartmouth College) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-480-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-480-2]
    - Louis Farrakhan: Michigan State University, undated; audiocassette; (Tape 1; Produced by The LightHouse) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-481-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-481-2]
    - Louis Farrakhan: Michigan State University, undated; audiocassette; (Tape 2; Produced by The LightHouse) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-482-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-482-2]
    - Sherman James: John Henryism and the Health of African Americans, undated; audiocassette; (Sherman James talk entitled "John Henryism and the Health of African Americans.") (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-483-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-483-2]
    - Heinz Klug: Defining the Property Rights of Others, undated; audiocassette; (Talk by Heinz Klug entitled "Defining the Property Rights of Others.") (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-484-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-484-2]
    - Earl Lewis: A Conversation with Myself about Race, undated; audiocassette; (Talk by Earl Lewis entitled "A Conversation with Myself about Race, Information, and Society.") (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-485-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-485-2]
    - Stella Taylor: Oral History Interview, undated; audiocassette; (Oral History interview with Stella Taylor.) (Box 36)
      - [side 1], [2012140-SR-486-1]
      - [Side 2], [2012140-SR-486-2]
- U-Matic Videotapes, 1971-1989
  - Undated
    - Central Michigan University students discussing being black; black men and black women; and being black at a white university, etc., Undated; [2012140-487]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 1:02:33) (Box 37)
      (Class discussion. Central Michigan University students discussing being black; black men and black women; and being black at a white university, etc.)
    - Harold Cruse, "AAS 699: Graduate Seminar" (Orientation Tape), Undated; [2012140-488]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 13:26) (Box 37)
      (Harold Cruse speaking about the course, History: 699 Graduate Seminar, interpretations of black history materials.)
    - Harold Cruse, "Black Literature, Objective Criticism of the Arts" (Interview), Undated; [2012140-489]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 59:09:00) (Box 37)
      (Interview with Harold Cruse, Professor of African and African American Studies. Conducted by William "Bill" Suttles.)
    - William Ford, "Blacks in the Contemporary Business World: Employment Problems" (Interview), Undated; [2012140-490]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 11:48) (Box 37)
      (Interview with William R. Ford, Director of Michigan Employment Security Commission. Conducted by Jon Lockard.)
    - Kathy Hoard, "AAS 100: Black Encounters;" Frank Yates, "AAS 203: Issues in Afro-American Development" (Orientation Tape), Undated; [2012140-491]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 28:13:00) (Box 37)
      (00:02) Kathy Hoard speaking about the course, AAS 100: Black Encounters, which explores one's relationship both with formal and informal black organizations. (14:45) Frank Yates speaking about the course AAS: 203: Issues in Afro-American Development, which concerns the growth and development of the community of black people among several dimensions.
    - Jim Ingram, columnist with the Michigan Chronicle (Interview), Undated; [2012140-492]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 23:03) (Box 37)
      (Interview with Jim Ingram, journalist and media personality. Conducted by Jon Lockard.)
    - Chokwe Lumumba, Republic of New Afrika (RNA) (Lecture), Undated; [2012140-493]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 1:01:59) (Box 37)
      (Lecture by Chokwe Lumumba, Minister of Justice of the Republic of New Afrika (RNA), speaking on the RNA and issues affecting the black community.)
    - Claudia Morcom, "AAS 450/451, The Black Community and the Law" (Orientation Tape), Undated; [2012140-494]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 4:39) (Box 37)
      (Claudia Morcom speaking about the course, AAS 450/451: The Black Community and the Law, which traces the historical evolution of the black man and his contacts with the legal system, as well as his struggle for equality and freedom.)
    - Cedric Robinson, "AAS 409: Charisma and African Diaspora" and "AAS 501: Anarchism and Violence" (Orientation Tape), 1973; [2012140-496]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 11:52) (Box 37)
      (Cedric Robinson speaking about the courses, AAS 409: Charisma and African Diaspora and AAS 501: Anarchism and Violence. Winter 1973.)
    - Trotter House and Meridian Junior College Gospel Choirs, Parts I and II, Undated
      - Part I, Undated; [2012140-497]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 1:01:44) (Box 38)
        (Concert performance by the Meridian Junior College Gospel Choirs at the Trotter House, Part I.)
      - Part II, Undated; [2012140-498]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 48:13:00) (Box 38)
        (Concert performance by the Meridian Junior College Gospel Choirs at the Trotter House, Part II.)
    - Godfrey Uzoigwe, "AAS: 530, African History Agricultural Revolution to 1800" (Orientation Tape), Undated; [2012140-499]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 24:00:00) (Box 38)
      (Godfrey Uzoigwe speaking about the course, AAS 530: African History.)
  - 1971
    - Sister Zubena Memorial (Cynthia Conley, d. 1971 February), [2012140-500]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 16:53) (Box 38)
      (Memorial for Sister Zubena (Cynthia Conley). (00:00) Speech on black womanhood. (14:39) "Callin' All Sisters")
    - Bethel A.M.E. Church Youth Choir. "Black Church and Music.", 1971 March; [2012140-501]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 53:47:00) (Box 38)
      (Youth Choir performance at the Bethel A.M.E. Church, with Reverend John A. Woods. Introduction by Artee Young.)
    - Imamu Amiri Baraka, "Black Nationalism, Theater, and Blacks in the Media" (Black Liberation Week), 1971 March; [2012140-502]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 50:37:00) (Box 38)
      (Lecture by Imamu Amiri Baraka during Black Liberation Week. Hill Auditorium.)
    - Imamu Amiri Baraka, "Discussing His School in Newark;" Jimmy Garrett, "On Education" (Interview), 1971 March; [2012140-503]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 56:27:00) (Box 38)
      (00:00) Interview with Imamu Amiri Baraka; lecturer, author, teacher, director, and critic. (14:16) Interview with Jimmy Garrett, Director of the Center for Black Education and playwright. Conducted by Artee Young. (43:05) Unidentified female speaker.
    - Jimmy Garrett; Philip Lee, "Independent Black Educational Institutions" (Black Liberation Week), 1971 March; [2012140-504]; 1 videotape (U-matic Videotape; b/w; sound; 1:01:48) (Box 38)
      (Symposium on Independent Black Educational Institutions. (2:20) Philip Lee, Malcolm X Liberation University, and (22:00) Jimmy Garrett, Director of the Center for Black Education.)